# **MATHEW THOMAS**

Phone: (832) 769-1153 9 Pine Cone Court, lovinmathew@hotmail.com Bloomington, IL 61704

Creative, detailed, and analytical engineering professional seeking to pursue a successful career in software engineering. Having 4 years of professional experience and looking to join a progressive tech company where my technical skills will be fully harnessed.

#### **EDUCATION**

### MSCS Georgia Institute of Technology

**August 2020 – Present** 

Master of Science in Computer Science (Online, Part-time)

# **Cert.** University of Texas Austin Boot Camps

**December 2019 – June 2020** 

Coding Bootcamp

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku

## **MEE** University of Houston

**August 2014 – May 2016** 

Master of Electrical Engineering

Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Systems, Digital Control Systems

### **B.Tech** Vellore Institute of Technology, India

**August 2009 – May 2013** 

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics

Computer Architecture, Data structures, Algorithms, Digital Signal Processing, Semiconductor Devices and Circuits, VLSI, Process Control

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# State Farm Insurance Company, Bloomington, IL

June 2020 – Present

Software Developer II (Full-Stack)

- •Worked on creating State farm Dashboard UIs using Node.JS, React.JS, Spring Boot and PostgresDB for agents to analyze and aggregate customer data. Co-developed with EY consultants to migrate existing customer data using Streamsets ETL pipelines and python libraries to Neo4j database. Worked on API development using GRAND stack for JSON responses using Neo4j DB.
- •AWS Managed AWS EC2 resources for cost management and familiar with session manager, Managed S3 buckets through State Farm's Public Cloud AWS CLI. Created Glue jobs for ETL processes.

#### Dow Inc., Baton Rouge, LA

July 2018 - August 2018

Process Automation Engineer

•Worked on FORTRAN based DOW control system (DOWTRAN) programming and automation projects. Tuned PID, constraint controllers and performed scale fraction math

calculations on DOWTRAN code. Performed code loads during turnarounds as per plant schedules.

•Created modern web based operator UI from legacy CAN diagrams using Javascript, HTML, CSS/SASS and Ajax/Axios calls for asynchronous APIs. Created CLIs using NodeJS, Server/routes using Express and stored user info on MySQL.

# Planet Forward (Contract), Houston, TX

**July 2018 - August 2018** 

Controls and Automation Engineer

•Developed web interface and linking of graphics from DCS server. Performed pre-fat testing with FDH JV team for Process, DCS and IPS graphics for Units 31 and 62.

## **Hargrove EPC, Houston, TX**

May 2017 - April 2018

Controls and Automation Engineer

DCS configuration and web linking of I/O points and modules on client's side server. Created responsive web pages for operators using Javascript, HTML, CSS/SASS and Ajax/Axios calls for asynchronous APIs.

- •Project 1: SI Group Honeywell TDC to Delta V Migration, Freeport, TX, May 2017.
- •Project 2: Albemarle JBC TPPBA Delta V Expansion, Safi, Jordan, August 2017.
- •Project 3: Total Honeywell Experion C300 Migration, La Porte, TX, November 2017.
- •Project 4: Lyondellbasell Equistar Honeywell Experion Migration, Westlake, LA, December 2017.
- •Project 5: Cardinal Group Shire UF/DF Skid Delta V Expansion, Lexington, MA, November 2017

### **BL Technology, Houston, TX**

March 2017 - May 2017

**Engineering Intern** 

- •Worked on City of Houston wastewater treatment plant's PLC replacement. Assisted the team on tag matching Siemens SIMATIC S7 300 PLC, HMI databases and web development.
- •Verified I/O module tags with CAD drawings. Prepared Operations and Maintenance manuals. Created responsive web pages to display manuals for clients using Javascript, HTML and CSS.

### **PROJECTS**

Coding Projects (UT Austin Bootcamps) <a href="https://portfolio-lmt.herokuapp.com/#Portfolio">https://portfolio-lmt.herokuapp.com/#Portfolio</a>	2020
Stability Control Using Pole Placement (University of Houston)	2015
MPEG Video Animation Using C (University of Houston) Awarded 3rd prize for video animation project, out of class total of 20 projects.	2014
Self-Healing of LTE Networks (VIT University)	2013